Inventory of the Annie G. Lyle papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Annie G. Lyle papers
1887-1941
1928-1932
XX496
Hoover Institution Archives
5 manuscript boxes (2.1 linear feet)
Correspondence, clippings, and campaign literature relating to Herbert Hoover and the American presidential elections of 1928 and 1932.
Lyle, Annie G.
Access
The collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
Annie Lyle was an American physician who practiced in the San Francisco and northern California regions. She was in the pioneer class of 1895 at Stanford University, where she befriended Herbert Hoover, and she eventually served as a Republican Party campaign worker, supporting Hoover during his presidential campaigns.
Scope and Content of Collection
The bulk of the collection consists of a large amount of printed matter, including newspaper clippings, concerning a variety of topics relating to political feelings of the time (1928-1932). The collection also contains articles, pamphlets, and other campaign materials authored by Lyle, detailing her support of Hoover, as well as correspondence received and sent by Lyle concerning campaign matters and Hoover. Of note is her working relationship with classmate Archie Rice in their work for the Hoover campaign, as evidenced by their correspondence and the co-authored "Political Sentiment Map of the United States."
Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964.; Republican Party (U.S.: 1854- ); Presidents--United States--Election--1928.; Presidents--United States--Election--1932.
- Correspondence, 1925-1932
  - Campaign mailing lists, 1928 (Box-folder 1: 1)
  - Between third parties, 1931-1932
    - From Crothers, G.E. to Norman, R.S., 1931 (Box-folder 1: 2)
    - From Hague, M. to Hall, 1931 (Box-folder 1: 3)
    - From Hale, M. to Hale, undated (Box-folder 1: 4)
    - From S., M.B. to Peck, M., 1932 (Box-folder 1: 5)
  - Received, 1925-1932
    - Rice, Archie, 1931-1932, undated (Box-folder 1: 6-8)
    - 1925 (Box-folder 1: 9)
    - July-August, 1928 (Box-folder 1: 10)
    - September, 1928 (Box-folder 1: 11)
    - October, 1928 (Box-folder 1: 12)
    - November-December, 1928 (Box-folder 1: 13)
    - 1929 (Box-folder 1: 14)
    - 1931 (Box-folder 1: 15)
    - January-March, 1932 (Box-folder 2: 1)
    - April, 1932 (Box-folder 2: 2)
    - May, 1932 (Box-folder 2: 3)
    - June-November, 1932 (Box-folder 2: 4)
    - Undated (Box-folder 2: 5)
  - Sent, 1926-1928, 1931-1932
    - 1928 (Box-folder 2: 6)
    - 1931 (Box-folder 2: 7)
    - 1932 (Box-folder 2: 8)
    - Telegram copies, 1926-1928 (Box-folder 2: 9)
- Printed Matter, 1887, 1922-1941
  - Newspaper clippings, 1929-1932
    Scope and Contents note
    Largely from the Washington Post, but also from the Los Angeles Times, San Francisco Chronicle, San Francisco Examiner, New York Times, Dallas Journal, and Saturday Evening Post. Folder titles are creator's.
    - Aliens, 1931-1932 (Box-folder 2: 10)
    - All American Nationalist Party, The Liberty Party (3rd Party), 1931-1932 (Box-folder 2: 11)
    - Cartoons, 1932 (Box-folder 2: 12)
    - Catholic, 1932 (Box-folder 2: 13)
    - Coalition, 1931 (Box-folder 2: 14)
    - Congress, 1931-1932 (Box-folder 2: 15)
    - Crime, 1932 (Box-folder 2: 16)
    - Democratic, 1929-1932 (Box-folder 2: 17)
    - Depression, 1931-1932 (Box-folder 2: 18)
    - Disarmament, 1931-1932 (Box-folder 2: 19)
    - Edison, 1931 (Box-folder 2: 20)
    - Education, 1932 (Box-folder 2: 21)
    - Garner, 1932 (Box-folder 2: 22)
    - General, 1929-1931 (Box-folder 2: 23)
    - German reparations, 1931 (Box-folder 2: 24)
    - Government ownership, undated (Box-folder 2: 25)
    - Great Smoky Mountain National Park, National Parks, 1931 (Box-folder 2: 26)
    - Hoover, Herbert, 1931-1932 (Box-folder 3: 1)
    - Illinois election, undated (Box-folder 3: 2)
    - Jefferson Day speeches, 1932 (Box-folder 3: 3)
    - Jews, 1932 (Box-folder 3: 4)
    - Jordan, Dr. David Starr, 1931 (Box-folder 3: 5)
    - Lewis, "Jim Ham,", undated (Box-folder 3: 6)
    - Lyle, Annie G., 1931 (Box-folder 3: 7)
    - MacDonald, Ramsay, 1931 (Box-folder 3: 8)
    - Masons, 1931-1932 (Box-folder 3: 9)
    - Miscellaneous, 1931-1932 (Box-folder 3: 10)
    - Mooney, 1932 (Box-folder 3: 11)
    - "Mourning Becomes Electorate,", 1932 (Box-folder 3: 12)
    - Murray, "Alfalfa Bill,", 1932 (Box-folder 3: 13)
    - Narcotics, undated (Box-folder 3: 14)
    - Navy, 1932 (Box-folder 3: 15)
    - Pinchot, 1931-1932 (Box-folder 3: 16)
    - Prohibition, 1931-1932 (Box-folder 3: 17)
  - "The American Freeman,", 1931-1932 (Box-folder 3: 18)
  - Better Health, 1928 (Box-folder 3: 19)
  - The Belief of Catholics and Liberal Protestants, pamphlet, undated (Box-folder 3: 20)
  - Biennial Convention of the National Women's Party, pamphlet, 1931 (Box-folder 3: 21)
  - Biographical Sketch of Hoover, pamphlet, 1928 (Box-folder 3: 22)
  - California HH "32" Club, pamphlet, 1932 (Box-folder 3: 23)
  - Campaign circulation, 1928-1932 (Box-folder 3: 24)
  - Campaign materials, 1928 (Box-folder 3: 25)
  - Herbert Hoover and the California Farmer, pamphlet, undated (Box-folder 3: 26)
  - How the Drys Will Meet the Wet Millionaire Challenge to Prohibition, pamphlet, undated (Box-folder 3: 27)
  - Informative Facts Concerning the President's Commissions, pamphlet, 1931 (Box-folder 3: 28)
  - Principle Not Politics, pamphlet, undated (Box-folder 3: 29)
  - List of Members of the California Medical Association, pamphlet, 1932 (Box-folder 4: 1)
  - Los Angeles Times, 1932 (Box-folder 4: 2)
  - The Literary Digest, 1929 (Box-folder 4: 3)
  - Mill Valley Record, 1931-1932 (Box-folder 4: 4)
  - Music and songs, 1928-1932 (Box-folder 4: 5)
  - News bulletins, 1930-1932 (Box-folder 4: 6)
  - Palo Alto Special to the Hoover Inaugural, pamphlet, 1929 (Box-folder 4: 7)
  - Photographs, 1887, undated (Box-folder 4: 8-9)
  - Postal Information, pamphlet, 1930 (Box-folder 4: 10)
  - "Republican National Committee," pamphlet, 1928 (Box-folder 4: 11)
  - Republican National Committee, newsletters, 1931-1932 (Box-folder 4: 12)
  - San Francisco Chronicle, 1928-1941 (Box-folder 4: 13)
  - The San Francisco Examiner, 1928-1929 (Box-folder 4: 14)
  - The Saturday Evening Post, 1928 (Box-folder 4: 15)
  - Stanford Illustrated Review, 1931-1932 (Box-folder 4: 16-20)
  - The Sun, undated (Box-folder 4: 21)
  - The Tammany I Know, newsletter, undated (Box-folder 4: 22)
  - "Ten Rules for Women Voters," leaflet, undated (Box-folder 5: 1)
  - War in Time of Peace, pamphlet, 1932 (Box-folder 5: 2)
  - What Is Proposition No. 2 on the Ballot to Be Voted on May 3, 1932?, pamphlet (Box-folder 5: 3)
  - What the Democratic Party Said It Would Do--What It Has Not Done, pamphlet, 1922 (Box-folder 5: 4)
  - White Ribbon Ensign, newsletter, 1928 (Box-folder 5: 5)
  - The Woman Voter, newsletter, 1931 (Box-folder 5: 6)
  - The Women's Division Republican National Committee, news bulletins, 1931 (Box-folder 5: 7)
  - "Political Sentiment Map of the United States,", 1931 (Box-folder 5: 8)
  - "Political Sentiment Map"-related correspondence, 1932 (Box-folder 5: 9)
  - Handkerchief, 1931 (Box-folder 5: 10)
- Writings by Others, 1928-1932
  - Cockerell, T.D., "Why Vote for Hoover?,", 1928 (Box-folder 5: 11)
  - Ellington, John, speech transcription, 1928 (Box-folder 5: 12)
  - Hickory, "A Platform for the Democrats,", 1932 (Box-folder 5: 13)
  - Long, Percy, "Speaker's Bulletin," published by the Republican State Committee, undated (Box-folder 5: 14)
  - McNab, John, "The Leadership of Herbert Hoover,", undated (Box-folder 5: 15)
  - Unidentified, "Personnel of National Prohibition Board of Strategy,", undated (Box-folder 5: 16)
- Speeches and Writings, 1928-1932
  - "Comparing Candidates' Careers" and related correspondence, 1928 (Box-folder 5: 17)
  - "The Human-ness of Hoover" and related correspondence, 1929 (Box-folder 5: 18)
  - "My Classmate--Herbert Hoover,", 1928 (Box-folder 5: 19)
  - "Reasons for My Support of Herbert Hoover,", 1928 (Box-folder 5: 20)
  - Notes, 1931-1932 (Box-folder 5: 21)
  - Transcription of speech, 1932 (Box-folder 5: 22)